Translated by Y.H.R.
Usually, our working day starts
with talking to criminals,
hobos,
and all kinds of unpleasant people.
But today,
we'll be talking to children.
It is so nice.
Kids are the most honest
and sincere people in the world.
Look, it's the coppers!
Balan, watch your vocabulary.
Hello kids.
Be seated, kids.
Hello.
Kids, today we'll be welcoming
uncle Serik and uncle Berik.
They are policemen.
Today, they'll be telling us about their line of work
Well, what's there to tell?
Our job is...
Come on, Berik, tell them.
- Why me?
- Go on, you got this.
For starters,
policemen uphold the law
we are law enforcers.
Let me tell you.
That's basically it.
Terrorists released the hostages.
And with one bullet,
he killed three terrorists.
That movie's sold on DVD.
It's called "Wanted".
Buy it yourselves, watch it home.
Yes, so is our hard job.
Like in the movie, but three times harder.
You're working so hard for such a pittance salary?
Well, turns out so.
Our jobs aren't so different actually.
There you have it, kids.
Any questions, kids?
Go on, kid.
What about bribery and corruption?
Did they prepare the questions or what?
Who told you that?
- My father.
- What does he do?
He's a prosecutor.
Well, he must be right then.
But it's other bad policemen.
Not us,
we're the good guys.
One more question?
You, kid.
Is it true, you beat people?
Who told you that?
My dad.
- What does he do?
- He's in the secret services.
Secret services you say.
Well, if he says so,
it's probably true.
But it's probably bad policemen.
Not us, we are the good guys.
We're not like that.
Another question? You, girl.
Do policemen really break the law?
Such a smart girl.
Your father's a lawyer, right?
No, my father is a plumber.
Hey, ask your dad "Kops (Liverpool) or Messi?".
You stupid? She's just a kid.
Further questions? You, boy.
Why do you always eat at Qaganat?
(Kazakh food chain)
Are you their guardians?
That does it with the questions.
I also think so.
Time to go, right?
Well, kids, after our story,
does anyone want to become
a policeman?
- Oh kid!
- There's one at least.
May I go to the bathroom?
Chief, let me go!
Hey pig, I have an appointment!
Hey watch your tongue
or I'll break your teeth.
Come and say it to my face.
Not man enough, huh?
I break a trainload of people like you.
A trainload you say?
Here we are, then.
End of the line.
Serik, if you had a son
would you make him a policeman?
Of course not.
Why? Let him sleep like a normal person,
and enjoy a regular life with family.
Why did you join the police if so?
I do not know.
My father always dreamed
that I became a policeman.
What about you?
My uncle knows all of them, cops.
Did he serve too?
No, he got arrested by them.
What a moron.
It's because of people like you
that we are hated.
These foreign workers are hard to catch
This one'll go to a cell himself
Hey, where are you going?
Have any papers?
(In Tajik)
(Talking about an embassy and papers)
What's he saying?
Who is he?
Seems to be speaking Tajik.
Sounds like it.
Do you have money?
(In Tajik)
Hey,  have "money"?
Yes, me. (Kha, mane)
What's he saying? I don't understand.
Let's take him.
Let's go, to the hotel.
"Beach hotel", 8-9 stars.
- Hey Mura.
- Hey.
Wow!
What's with your eye?
Did Janishka arrive?
Yes, she did.
Funny isn't it?
We called the capital,
we warned the secret services.
We'll find your cat.
Don’t forget that my cat
is pregnant.
Oh she's also pregnant?
Then we'll call international detectives
and alert interpol.
Okay, we’ll find your cat.
Thank you.
No problem.
- Goodbye.
I've had it with these grandmas.
Hey, take it easy.
Hello.
Mura, process this one.
Will do.
Who's this?
Some Tajik apparently.
Or God knows who.
Let him stay here for now.
Then send him to immigration police.
Why should he sit and do nothing?
Let him paint the corridor.
Really?
Sure, no worries.
Just restrain him.
Don't worry.
Let's go.
What's up? Anything for us?
Yes, here you go.
Basically, there's a photo with
some Tajik ambassador on it.
He disappeared yesterday night
after going to a store.
Maybe he was robbed.
There's nothing on him.
No money nor papers.
He only speaks Tajik.
Maybe that's our guy?
Maybe he is.
Don't joke about guys.
It's a serious matter.
It comes from our boss.
He'll have to serve.
Yes? If the boss says so.
Alright then.
Shouldn't you get a divorce for that?
This can't come to this.
No, it's not her, it's okay.
- Oh yes?
- Yes, everything's okay.
- Bye.
Hey, stitch-guy.
Why are you quiet?
To be fair, if I got beaten.
I'd also keep quiet.
You're asking for it, scumbag.
Listen.
I always wanted to ask.
Who do you want first?
A boy or a girl?
Well, first money,
a car, then get on my feet.
Only then kids.
Oh? So said my brother.
See? Your brother gets it.
No, you don't understand.
My brother's already 50.
And he has none of that.
People are different, brother.
Oh I don’t know.
Alright, let's go.
We have to find that ambassador.
Start with the store.
- How much, mate?
- 200 Tenge.
200 Tenge.
Showed him the ambassador’s photo?
I did.
Damn, I forgot the chewing gum.
Be quick.
Oh mate, look carefully.
Have you seen him?
No, I haven't.
Alright, mate.
Thank you (In Kazakh)
Let's reflect.
What do you mean?
What's there to think about?
I'll do the thinking,
don’t worry.
Suppose, I am a foreigner.
I only speak Tajik.
I walk around town.
And don't know what to do.
What would I do?
I'd seek the Tajiks.
Where do we have many of them?
In Tajikistan, obviously.
Are you usually this stupid?
Actually, you always are.
I'm talking about here.
In tire shops and on construction sites.
That's it then.
Let's start by looking there.
We'll be the immigration police for now.
- Right?
- Right.
Let’s do a population census.
Oh by the way, there are also a lot in doners.
Seriously? It's Turks in doners.
How do you distinguish them?
I just studied.
I didn't become a policeman through relatives.
I graduated.
Also, I have a better education.
Guys, I'm being honest.
There're no Tajiks here.
Only locals work here.
Trust me.
Hey, locals don't work for so cheaply.
Honestly, they do.
Mikhail, cement got delivered.
Your signature is needed.
Alexander, I'm busy right now.
You've one just like ours, right?
- Seems so.
- Can I see?
Sure.
So if I say something
everyone will hear me, right?
Everyone will hear, yes.
Alex, send all the Tajiks down.
We have no Tajiks.
Mikhail, you said it like a cop.
Enough joking around.
Send the Tajiks down here.
I am joking, I’ll send them.
I can’t do it now.
Work will stop otherwise.
Wow, seems someone's in trouble.
You guys, I didn’t know,
believe me.
Of course, how could you have known?
Let’s go.
Guys, we need your help.
- Know him?
- No, we don't.
Maybe you saw him somewhere?
- No, we didn't.
- Look carefully.
How about you?
From which company?
What's that? He's from the embassy.
I don't know that organisation.
Organisation...
What will we do with them?
Deport them, that's all.
Right, what else?
No other option, right?
Wait, let's come to an agreement.
Remember the address?
No, I remember everything clearly.
Garden Boulevard 3, Apartment 13.
I'll send you 3 tile workers.
Tomorrow morning.
I'm keeping an eye on you.
Berik, is it settled?
Let's go.
By the way, do you need a tile worker?
I need an ambassador, mate.
Time's running away.
Let's go, seriously.
Chief, take your baton back.
Or maybe you're scared?
It's not my baton.
Not anymore.
Hey chief, heard this parable?
In ancient Sparta, puny and ugly kids
were thrown down from a hill.
Looks like someone survived
and made it to the duty desk.
What are you hinting at?
I’m not hinting,
I’m telling it to your face
that you’re a sucker.
Hey, cut the trash talk.
Come and make me.
This is it.
Say your prayers, you bastard.
Buddy, have you seen this man?
No chief, I don't know him.
Call the other hobo.
Zhaqsleq (Goodness in Kazakh), come here.
You have such positive names.
Zhaqsleq, Quanys (Joy), Satleq...
Zhaqsleq, have you seen this man?
I haven't.
Don't look at me, but here.
Haven't seen him.
Your eyes say that you've been boozing.
Where's this guy?
Quane, will you fight him?
Right now, chief?
What do you think?
I have an appointment.
Appointment?
Just admit you're scared.
No, chief
I'm always ready when you ask.
You always lose.
This bag's hindering me, that's why.
Don't use the bag as an excuse,
you're scared.
Anyway, if you see him.
Call me, alright?
Oh right, you don't have any phones.
Chief, leave me your number
I'll call from my friend Nadezhda's phone.
Scram already.
Oh wait.
Here's my card.
Call me, alright?
If you see him.
Have you settled it?
They're of no use.
Oh yes?
Let's eat at the Uzbek's restaurant?
Yes, hungry policemen are less effective.
Have any money by the way?
What money? You suggested this.
So why did we come?
Let's go
- Let's do as usual then?
- As usual?
As we always do.
Think.
Salam alajkum.
Akbar, how are you?
- Fine, you.
- Great.
Akbar, I heard you hired new cooks
right?
- That's right.
What to they cook?
Eastern food, laghman noodles, manti dumplings, plov rice.
Show me the cook's passport.
Here it is.
He's registered with an authorisation.
Everything's by the book?
Yes, by the book.
- Where were you born?
- In Italy.
- In the Ural mountains or something?
- No.
Alright, here.
Well done.
Bring me a kebab then.
Just a kebab?
Want one too?
Just one for me.
Fine.
Oh wait.
Have you seen this guy?
- No.
- Did he come to relax or have tea?
I am afraid I haven't seen him.
- You sure? Look again.
- I am sure.
- Green tea also.
- Alright.
Hey, punchbag.
Do you even practice sports?
Shut your mouth!
Salam Mura,
What's with your face?
Is it Janeshka?
Yes, sure Janeshka did it.
Don't take it badly mate.
Watch Tarzan.
I'll be back.
What?!
Won't it bite?
No, it doesn't bite the police.
So you don’t bite the police, huh?
Brace yourself, you punk.
Tarzan, attack!
Hey Mura,
What happened to the dog?
It ran out to the street
and got hit by a car.
Damn it, Mura.
I can't even trust you with this?
Doesn't seem to be so serious.
Hey beastmaster, how's it going?
Chief, how's Tarzan doing?
Shut your mouth.
You won't leave me in peace.
Face the wall.
Mura, what's up?
Alright.
Good lord, what happened?
It's all fine, just a cold.
How can I help you?
I'm in a hurry
Is there a free solitary cell?
Yes, there.
Please, take him in.
I have to go.
Just  be careful with him.
He broke five jawbones.
Why're you buckling up?
Look, traffic police.
- Are you stupid?
- Oh, it wasn't them.
What's all this fuss about?
You know this number?
Three seven, all five.
I don’t know it.
Some cool guy is calling.
Maybe it's the boss.
Yes, hello?
Hello,
- This is Quanys.
- What Quanys?
Quanys of Astana (Capital)?
No, of course.
You asked me to call when
I saw your ambassador.
Oh,  it's you hobo?
You should have said
you're the drunkard hobo.
I'm not a hobo.
Whatever hobo,
what's up?
Found the ambassador?
Just calling to tell you,
this is my number, write it down.
Alright then.
The hobo is ringing.
How do they get phones?
This fuss again.
Three sevens, all nines.
Know the number?
I don’t know
maybe some other bum.
Yes, maybe that plastic bag guy.
What's going on this time?
Hello.
Chief, this is my second number.
Hey alcoholic, hobo.
Don’t call here anymore, got it?
Punk.
That hobo again.
Where do they get these numbers?
Another thing to investigate.
Is it true?
You broke 5 jawbones?
No, that's nonsense.
I broke 7.
Want me to get you released?
I have no money.
No need for money.
Just take care of some hobo.
No, I don’t beat hobos or kids.
I see.
Alright, where is he?
It's not just any hobo.
Be careful with him.
He has a killer left jab.
Wait.
Full contact.
- You're free to go.
- Oh damn!
That'll teach you not to show off again.
- Scumbag.
- Screw you.
Hey Mura, send the Tajik out, alright?
I'll drive him away, yes.
Make him bring a bucket of water and a rag.
Understood?
Good.
Listen up.
Wash the entire car, from here to here.
Ok?
Then that's it, "go home".
(In Tajik)
What do you mean "go home"?
I need to get to my embassy.
Why? No need to wash the interior.
Just the outside.
Wash everywhere.
Understood?
Oh so you understand Tajik now?
A very easy language, it turns out.
Go on.
Come on now.
Let's see it.
Rub hard, ok?
Get all the oil and grime off.
We changed the oil yesterday.
There isn't much.
Come on, hurry up.
(In Tajik)
I want to smoke. (?)
Done washing?
Did a good job?
Looks quite alright.
Alright, go wash your face.
Then go at the duty desk to be dismissed.
Go wash up.
(In Tajik)
Face, wash your face.
Then come back.
Go on.
Serik, where do we look
for our ambassador now?
I don't know.
We'll find him.
Is your face clean, now?
We'll get to the bottom of it.
Let's drive.
(Lost foreigner)
(In Tajik)
What a decent Tajik.
Not Tajik but Jacket.
Good lord.
Here.
Ayran. (Salted yoghurt)
Something to eat.
Give him the whole plastic bag.
So, go straight
then right. The embassy is there.
(In Tajik)
I said straight ahead then right.
There's Tajikistan's embassy.
Go. Move along.
Let's go.
That's how the next day ended.
In our line of work
today is never the same as yesterday.
Today is never like tomorrow.
But we always hope that tomorrow
will be better than today.