Translated by Y.H.R.
There are many kinds of professions in the world.
Some are prestigious, others less so.
Well, I have the most prestigious one in the world.
And people, relate to us differently.
The biggest law offenders, are the police themselves.
All they care about is finding flaws,
they're all idiots.
What's there to say about them?
When these cops are here, it's a bloody mess.
What are they good for?
I don't even know who I should fear most
criminals, or the cops themselves.
We are regular people, not villains.
It's just that our line of work is different from everyone's.
As soon as something happens to people,
we're the first ones they come running to.
Praised be our honourable policemen.
If it weren't for you...
Dear policemen, what would be without you.
They're my saviours.
If it weren't for them, I could have been killed.
Real men.
(In Kazakh)
What would we do without you.
Here you have it,
our work isn't always valued.
Some understand us, others don't.
Regardless of all the hurdles,
I love my work.
I am proud to be a policeman.
Serik
Actor: Rustem Omarov
Berik
Actor: Mejrzhan Turbaev
Mura
Actor: Mejirkhan Shernjazov
Chef
Actor: Adilzhan Shombolov
Edil. Actor: Edil Anarbaj
Medet. Actor: Medet Amanbaev
Patrol
Since my childhood,
I've dreamt of becoming a policeman.
Being part of valiant upholders of the law is very difficult.
I worked diligently, to fulfill my dream.
To become a policeman,
I had to graduate with honours.
4 years of legal education.
2 more years of higher police academy.
Only then, did I finally get to wear
these long-awaited epaulettes.
As it turns out, for some people,
there is a shortcut to that journey.
(In Kazakh)
Berik, come in. (Kazakh)
Salam alajkum.
Congratulations. (Kazakh)
Just like that,
a bad apple spoils the whole barrel.
I just got pulled over illegally by the police.
We'll find out why.
Just because some illiterate people
accidentally end up in law enforcement agencies,
us, the police are hated.
Your papers.
On what basis?
and why aren't you introducing yourself?
Huh?
Why aren't you doing this by the book?
Answer, you are being recorded.
What's going on, mate?
Give me the camera,
it's mine, mate.
And this is our chief.
Head of the Chapaev district police department.
The police major.
Usually, those in such a position,
own an expensive jeep,
a large cottage, and only eat in restaurants.
But our boss is not like that.
He is honest and modest.
Drives an ordinary car,
lives in an ordinary flat.
And doesn't eat in restaurants.
The most expensive thing he owns is an iPhone
which was gifted to him.
Yes.
Hello.
So, how is the sound quality?
Great, right?
Well, what do you mean?
It's an iPhone after all.
- Yes?
- Chief, may I?
Come in.
Alright, I'll call you back later.
- Salam alajkum
- Wa alajkum salam
I'm Murat, Sarsenbaj's son.
(Kazakh)
I know your father well.
Back in the days,
the whole town was praying for us.
Why?
We were the best motor mechanics.
No one but us could disassemble a tractor's motor.
I just read your resume right now, it's funny.
So you are the drawing champion of the Kokmorsk ditrict?
I am.
Graduated second best.
(Mispronouncing in Kazakh instead of Russian)
(Correcting prononciation)
Your astrological sign is cancer.
Chinese year of the ox.
Very useful information.
That's exactly why we need guys like you.
Who filled out the resume?
I did.
- I bet you did.
- I gave it my best.
Who do you want to be?
Well, I want to be in secret service.
Or make it somewhere up in the ministry.
For now, you'll be on duty desk,
then we'll see how you manage.
- Ok?
- Ok.
"Yes sir" should be your answer.
Forget about being a civilian.
You're a duty officer now
of the Chapaev district, no less.
Whoever walks into our precinct will see you first.
- Understood?
- Understood.
Get that rubbish off your eye.
You're the face of our precinct now.
That's it, dismissed.
By the way, do you know where the bluetooth is?
No bluetooth.
I only have municipal phones
Fine, dismissed.
Such freedom when walkie-talkies are quiet.
If only it were forever.
They'll be quiet all day.
Oh yeah?
Did you read that in the horoscope?
No, why?
I just turned off the volume.
What do you mean?
You turned off our walkie-talkie?!
Well yes,
this way, we aren't bothered.
Are you stupid?
I've never seen someone do that.
You idiot.
#3 what the hell's going on?! Do you copy?
Over.
#3 copy.
Robbery in your area, proceed urgently.
Why aren't you answering?
Copy, we are on our way.
We just have a bad network here.
Your penatly will be as bad as your network.
Alright, we are on our way.
You moron, let's go.
What about the food?
Bring it with you.
It's better if I bring it in me.
Suit yourself, just do it quickly.
Come on already.
I used to imagine the life of a policeman as in Holywood movies.
Reality is otherwise.
Hey, go sleep elsewhere.
But today, we have a more serious assignement.
By the way, my name is Serik.
I'm a regular patrolman.
I've been patrolling every corner of this district
for 9 years.
As you guessed,
this goblin is my new partner, Berik.
Why goblin?
Because you're still a greenhorn.
Well, well, well...
Slow down, we have some offender.
(In Kazakh)
He got scared away.
You're still a little bit of a moron.
Who are you constantly talking to?
Talking to myself.
As if I could talk to someone else.
Your boxing madness
has knocked the brains out of you.
You shouldn't have take up boxing.
You should have taken up boxing.
To make you use your brain.
What are you talking about?
A lot of boxers and wrestlers mess up in life.
Wrestlers are always stronger.
Where did you see that?
Just look at the UFC.
There, boxers don't stand a chance at all.
Wrestlers dominate.
Just don't watch the women's UFC
and you'll be fine, got it?
This isn't women's UFC.
Shut up now, we have arrived.
You have something, does it hurt?
At last.
What took you so long?
We've been waiting for 2 hours.
What happened, miss?
He was robbed.
And while you were coming,
he was robbed again.
Hey lady, cut the jokes and the orgasms.
Alright?
Sarcasm*
Oh right, sarcasm.
Don't you worry.
I don't get it
I was walking, then 2 guys jumped me.
What a disaster.
As they attacked you,
and robbed you, did they say anything?
Well, of course...
they greeted him and apologised.
They robbed him then called you.
Move along, miss.
Who are you?
I'm a mother.
What? His mother?
No, I have two kids.
I don't want this happening to them.
Everything will be alright with your kids.
Your kids will always be healthy and all.
Move along now.
Please, don't bother us.
We have it under control.
Remember how they looked?
Basically, one had a red-gray jacket
with a blue sweater
and a cap with "Abidas" written on it.
- Wow.
- Such accuracy, mate.
How can you remember such details?
Well, these were my own clothes.
Alright, let's go.
We'll figure it out, driving around.
Wait, where are you taking him?!
We'll take him where needed.
Come on miss.
To the police station,
where else?
I bet you'll leave him on the road somewhere
as if nothing happened.
Are you crazy?
We're taking him to the station.
before looking for the criminals.
- Where is your station?
- On Shevchenko.
Oh wait, perhaps you could give me a ride then.
Lady, it's not our way.
We need to work.
Ok, fine.
Then I'll report you arrived 2 hours late.
Alright, fine.
- Thanks, you guys are the best.
- Come on.
This is Mura's first day.
He probably figured he'd be locking up bandits
racketeers, or drug mules.
But for now,
it's only drunkards.
(In Kazakh)
Hello Mura. (Kazakh)
Open up.
Let him sober up then release him.
- Ok?
- Ok.
Who's this?
A criminal, right?
Are you serious?
(In Kazakh)
Sober up, then we'll release you.
Ok?
Where are we even going?
Patroling around.
If we don't find them,
we'll fill in your report.
Guys,
do you think he's that stupid?
To wear my stuff,
in this neighbourhood even?
Of course, he's stupid
He'd be at university otherwise.
Or at least, would have found a job.
Instead of doing all this nonsense.
That's "elemantary", mate.
We say "elementary".
It's better if I go home.
That's all right, just forget it.
Hey, that's not "advocuate".
How would we find the suspect without you?
Adequate*
(Radio) #1, do you copy?
Will we actually get him?
Don't worry, matey.
We've eaten sheep.
(Expression: I know what I'm doing)
We've eaten dog*
(Correcting expression)
No, it's the Koreans who eat dog.
We eat sheep.
That's the truth.
Well, well...
(In Kazakh)
Do this again,
and I'll bash your head in.
- I'm just joking.
- Whatever.
Come on.
(In Kazakh)
What?
- I said come on, we've arrived.
- Oh, I see.
This stinks.
Hey!
Oh, salam alajkum, man.
What's up?
Have you gone rotten or what?
It's really bad.
How?
Something smells?
You don't say!
It's a bloody stench.
I probably ate something wrong then.
You ate a hobo you mean.
Something's bloody decaying in here.
Get out of here at least.
Basically, we have a description
of someone with a red jacket.
I can't stand this stench.
You carry on.
If you see someone with a red jacket,
no need to arrest him.
Just bring him here,
and let him die.
What a stench!
Hey guys, are you coming for lunch?
No.
I don't get what smells.
Everything's fine.
Hey, chief.
Let me out, I'm sober.
Keep it down.
My colleague will come and release you.
(In Kazakh)
It's not my call.
Mura, here you go.
Hold still.
Face the wall.
Step back.
Let's go.
The cell.
- Almas?
- Mura ?
Move it.
Your hands.
You alright, Almas?
As you can see, I am not.
What happened?
I was framed.
You were framed?
Sure, it's not your fault.
Someone beat up a woman
took her phone
and purely by chance gave it to you.
(In Kazakh)
- See you.
- Bye.
Angela, do you have a minute?
What?
Don't act innoncent.
You can't loiter.
Come here.
I know that already.
I have to make a living somehow.
You are very attractive.
And what do you do?
Sell Pirogi, like an idiot?
Prostitution would earn you much more.
Screw you.
Angela.
Forgive him,
he's joking.
Angela,
Did you have a customer in a red jacket by chance?
I won't tell you anyway.
Hey...
don't make me find cocaine on you.
I'm asking you nicely.
Alright, chief.
There was a guy in a red jacket.
He headed north.
That way?
North is that way.
Are you stupid?
Hey, watch it.
I know where it is.
(In Kazakh)
Alright, thank you Angela.
Bye, Snow White.
I'll cut that finger off.
Come on, Mura.
We've been former classmates
for a long time
You could let me go?
I can't, mate.
Really.
Talk to your boss, then?
I can't, it's my first day at work.
Understood.
Could you expect we would meet again after so long?
I didn't expect this either.
Remember how we used to like the same girl?
I do remember.
Inara?
I liked her very much too
but I let you have her.
You're like a brother to me.
Sorry brother, I can't just release you.
No need, brother.
I way just reminiscing.
Remember when you broke the school window?
I had taken the fall for you.
I remember.
I was almost expelled because of it.
Fine, I'll go.
Talk to your boss?
No, going to the toilets.
Ajgul?
I don't care!
Brothers, relatives, classmates.
It's all the same to me.
Everyone is equal before the law.
While patrolling
looking for robbers
one might run into peculiar people.
Hey junkie, what you doing here?
Why junkie?
You have no right to talk to me this way.
Talk to me by the book please.
Hey buddy,
I'll bring you in if you continue.
Why are you naked?
Where in the penal code is it written
that walking naked in the street is forbidden?
Alright, man.
Forgive us, mister. Sorry
The law (in Kazakh)
So long, smart guy.
What gives you the right to say "so long"?!
You're on duty!
Address me by the book.
Oh, hello, north south east west.
Basically, there was a robbery.
The suspect was in a red jacket
Did you see anything?
No, we saw nothing.
Are you even working?
Of course we are.
Every dog knows us here.
Dog?
When will people know you?
They're not guiding at all.
Let's ask these punks
if they saw anything.
I don't understand, are they getting high?
Obviously, they don't wash their bottles.
They're crazy.
How's the relaxation going, guys?
At least wash the bottles, right?
Junkies don't run that way.
Yes, definitely.
How do they do it?
Yes, Mura.
I figured you couldn't help
Brother,
in this situation I can't help you at all.
Do you remember
when the highschool bully
wanted to steal your money?
Well, I helped you.
- When will you bring it?
- We warned you.
- Where is the money?
- We were clear about it.
Hey, leave Mura alone.
What did you say?
- Leave him
- Come here!
I always took the fall for your blunders.
I kept silent.
Murat, why did you tear up the magazine?
Miss, I did it.
Murat,
why did you blow a firecracker in the toilets?
Sir, I did it.
- Almas, was it you?
- Yes.
Murat, why are you cussing at girls?
Miss, it was me cussing.
Almas,
did you trample all the flowers by the school?
Yes Murat?
Yes, he did it.
It's over, we won't find him.
Hey, have some patience.
There is no rush.
No, we won't find anyone.
Let's record your statement.
How about driving me home?
What's the address?
Shevchenko-Kirova.
How much?
700?
Let's go.
Let's have some fun, right?
Sir, my son ended up here.
Murat?  Is that you?
(In Kazakh)
Almas is here, can you help him?
Mom, don't bother asking.
He can't help.
(In Kazakh)
Why are you shouting?
What did you?
I just got involved with the wrong people.
So?
You really can't help?
It's no use
He can't help.
He tried.
We have always been like a family.
You played together in our house.
You really can't help?
(In Kazakh)
Almas, you are free to go.
But it's your first day at work.
It will be alright.
Go
Thank you (in Kazakh)
Thank you brother.
You truly won't get in trouble?
No, our boss is a good person.
Hey dummy,
what have you done?
Already messing up on your first day.
I don't care if it's your friend, classmate or relative.
The law applies to everyone.
Yes?
You're in luck.
The victim withdrew his complaint.
Otherwise you'd be out of here.
Permission to speak.
You may.
Where did you get this souvenir from?
Is it from Dubai, by any chance?
Today was a waste, if I'm frank.
We're just burning fuel away.
Yes, that's how it is.
A waste of time.
Oh look, isn't that...
It's our suspect, right?
The jacket matching  the description.
Yes, let's go!
I almost broke my shoulders.
Well, wasn't I right?
Boxing is better than wrestling.
Here we go again.
If I didn't grab him, he'd have run away.
Mate, it's my punch that made him motionless.
Don't start.
(Radio)
To all units,
the red jacket suspect
has been apprehended.
Over and out.
I'll be damned.
Who did I wrestled?
#3 copy.
Damn, let's go apologise.
Yes, let's.
This is so embarrassing.
Hey, come here.
What more do you want?
I already gave you everything.
Just have your jacket back.
Don't lie you bastards.
You want my shoes now, don't you?
What do we need them for?
- Come here!
- Screw you!
Boxing, wrestling.
It's athletics we should be doing.
Hey, boxing is always the best.
Got it?
It's just that I haven't trained in a while.
(In Kazakh)
It's like this every day.
I just got home from work.
Yet, it's already time to head back.
I don't know if there is a heaven
and if policemen end up there.
I'd like to believe there is.
I don't know either if there's a place for me there.
What I am sure about though
is that I'll oversleep all I want there.